<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>search - Category - Software Tech Blog</title>
        <link>https://faheem-nadeem.github.io/categories/search/</link>
        <description>search - Category - Software Tech Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://faheem-nadeem.github.io/categories/search/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Hydra—Kubernetes based Dataset PubSub and Volume Management System</title>
    <link>https://faheem-nadeem.github.io/hydra/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://faheem-nadeem.github.io/hydra/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/posts/hydra/thumbnail.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>In the previous articles of this advent series, we described the architecture of our search engine and highlighted technologies which help us serve search results.
After many iterations on our architecture, we are finally on a microservice architecture pattern, driven through a container orchestration platform: Kubernetes. This brought us many engineering improvements, but it also has introduced new challenges, such as, the ability to perform a dataset propogation via Pub-Sub, along with volume management for microservices.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>The Architecture of a Large-Scale Web Search Engine</title>
    <link>https://faheem-nadeem.github.io/architecture-of-large-scale-web-search-engine/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://faheem-nadeem.github.io/architecture-of-large-scale-web-search-engine/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/posts/architecture-of-large-scale-web-search-engine/serp.gif" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>In previous posts of this series, we have described some of the technologies that power our private search products. It is about time that we introduce the systems that bring everything together. It is important to understand that a web scale search engine is highly complex. It is a distributed system with strong constraints on performance and latency. On top of that it can easily become extremely costly to operate; both in human resource and, of course, in money.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
